- All right, now we can fully start.
Welcome, thank you again so much for your patience.
Sorry about the delay.
I did create a song.
It was supposed to be an anthem for us.
These were the lyrics that you are going to read
as you enjoyed the song,
but unfortunately we are out of time.
So, if you are curious about the song,
I'll be happy to email you the link.
And also, this is not a paid advertisement for Suno,
but usually when I talk I like to create anthems.
And what I use is Suno AI, it is free,
but you could pay like $8, $9
if you are so into music that you want it to be customized.
All right, so I would like to start off
just by welcoming you and welcoming our panelists.
I'll be the moderator for today.
My name is Leslie Flores Valmonte.
I teach work experience over at Chaffey College.
I, at one point for seven years,
was a Guided Pathways regional coordinator
for our state.
And now all I do is AI.
So thank you again for having us, for joining us today.
As I was preparing for this moment,
I started thinking about the concept of digital twins.
And it reminded me
of how I have always wanted my own J.A.R.V.I.S.
So how many of us have seen Ironman?
Yes, okay.
So who wants their own J.A.R.V.I.S., right?
Yes, so I'm excited
because I feel like I finally get that chance
to have my own J.A.R.V.I.S.,
but there is caution, right?
That we should take along with having the fun
and also the responsibility.
Because in "Iron Man" the movie,
we saw how it was Robert Downey Jr. psychic, right?
It was Iron Man's protector,
you know, like almost like savior at some point
during the fight.
But I'm not sure which movie it was.
But we also saw at one point
when J.A.R.V.I.S. got hacked, right?
Yeah, and so to me, I feel like,
you know, there's a lesson to be learned.
We each will have our own J.A.R.V.I.S., how we train it,
and also how we care for making sure
that it's not exhibiting risky behavior,
and how we're implementing guardrails, right?
It's going to be so important
because we know that at any given moment
our J.A.R.V.I.S. can turn against us
and that's the last thing that we want.
So, yes, while it is all fun and games
having a digital twin, there must be something
to be said of always making sure that,
you know, humanity comes first, right?
Our own personal wellness comes first.
So with that, I would like to pass this on to our panel.
And if you can just take one minute to introduce your name,
how you serve our students,
and 15 seconds to describe
how your personal J.A.R.V.I.S. is.
Any values, principles?
I'll pass it on to you, you first.
- Hi, I'm Bob Cormia.
I teach chemistry at Foothill College
and I did lose my voice an hour ago.
I was pretending I was yelling at my students
in the lab, right?
Seriously, I do teach chemistry stem at Foothill,
and I've been working with my colleagues,
especially my dean, Zach Cembellin, on AI projects,
and picked up an interesting term from our chancellor,
Lee Lambert, who has a digital twin.
And I'll be sharing that idea with you today.
Oh. - Is that one up?
- Yeah, this is not gonna go.
- Is that one up? - Yeah, it's fine.
Hi, I am Drew Magliozzi, CEO of Mainstay,
and we are an AI-powered college coaching platform
that focuses on human relationships first and foremost.
Specifically the relationship between the student
and their counselor to enhance the journey to
and through college and into careers.
And my personal, I mean, I like to talk to ChatGPT
about the hair-brained ideas I have
that I'm too ashamed to talk to other people about.
And it is, you know, very encouraging
but sometimes a little too encouraging.
'cause I think the best ideas often start out as bad ideas,
but most of them probably should never see the light of day.
So, yeah, that's my personal usage.
- Hi, I'm Vinny Forese.
I'm the CEO of Link-Systems International.
We are NetTutor.com, an online tutoring company
that works directly with 105
of the 115 community colleges here in California,
providing live one-on-one tutoring to your students.
And I don't really know
that I have a personal J.A.R.V.I.S.
like that quite just yet.
- There's still time.
- Okay, so it's my turn.
I do have a personal avatar that I like to showcase.
This is basically- - Oh, you need a mic, here.
Michelle, here, take this.
- So I do have a creative digital avatar
for myself as introduction.
That being said, following this morning's
Chancellor Lee Lambert's introduction.
Instead of me talk about how great I am,
my digital twin gonna talk about how great I am.
Let me go ahead and just play it.
- [Michelle Wu Twin Avatar] Hi, I am the digital twin
of Michelle Wu.
I have a strong passion for education and technology,
and I believe AI can greatly enhance
the learning experience for students.
By incorporating AI into education,
we can personalize learning,
provide real-time feedback and support,
and improve overall student engagement and success.
In addition to teaching and developing AI,
I also mentor students in various hackathons
and innovation challenges.
My background in business, computer engineering and AI
has allowed me to see the potential and impact
of this technology in various industries.
I am excited to see how AI will continue to shape
and improve the education.
Thank you.
- Thank you. - By the way,
the script is kind of AI-generated with my modification,
so I'm not gonna take all the credit
that I wrote such a great bio.
- Thank you, Michelle.
So, how many of us were impressed by the avatar?
Hasn't it gotten just exponentially better than,
maybe a year, a year and a half ago?
- Yeah. - Yeah.
I had one and I showed it to my daughter
and it was so creepy 'cause it was just kind of,
like, the mouth, like the puppet,
that she literally told me, like, "Turn it off!"
(attendees laughing)
So I haven't updated yet, but I'm inspired now to see,
like, how much better it can get.
All right, so let's get into it.
My first question is to Michelle and Robert.
What does a digital twin look like in the classroom, a lab,
a campus system, and why should we care?
- Well, you know, students email us 24 hours a day
with all kinds of crazy questions.
Like, I have strep throat, should I come to lab?
I said, yes, and you might, but don't kiss anyone, right?
You wanna teach your avatar to answer basic questions.
What should I wear the first day?
Well, shoes are a good idea, right?
How do I succeed in class?
Well, stay up on your homework, right?
What do I do if I miss a lab?
Now that's an important question, right?
Because there's a set of questions.
I don't want them to be scared off.
Don't come to lab sick, so here's what you do.
And your TAs, when the students ask a question like,
I cannot figure out gas laws.
And I might say, well, join the club,
but there's a path to get there.
And I train my TA how to step a student
through the four variables, put it all together,
and then we do some reinforcement dialogue.
So the TA really represent what an instructor would do
in an office hour, right?
But we have to train our TA
to be a good representation of us.
- Yes, I definitely agree
with what the Professor Cormia said.
Digital twin is not a new concept.
It has been existing in the industry for years
or maybe even for decade.
Think about the construction, think about healthcare,
think about the automobile
that they will provide or fabricate.
A not so much of digital twin,
but the model before they deploy,
especially with the construction.
You build a building so you have a little mini building.
That's not digital twin, but that's a modeling.
We call them modeling a twin, right?
Then you can make modifications,
you can do cost estimation, operation.
And then, that got scale and fast forward
into what we call the digital twin.
So digital twin does not only...
This digital twin for education is a niche,
it's a special application out of this bigger digital twin,
such as manufacturing.
BMW have implemented their digital twin of manufacturer
that they can go ahead to test ideas,
test drives on everything
before they put a lot of money into a real manufacturer.
As a teacher, I kind of take advantage of this, I said,
"Well, you know, what Bill Gate said,
if you wanna get your job done, done the best,
you'll find the laziest worker."
I'm not saying I'm the laziest.
But I find efficient way to utilize the AI technology
to help me be more available,
to help my student in the classroom
that they have number of questions they wanna ask.
I don't like to study, but I wanna pass my class.
What do I do, right?
So the AI is very smart to very articulate in a way to say,
this is very hard course,
you do have to put in lots of effort
if you wanna get a good grade.
As a real Professor Wu will say,
well, you know, you gotta have to study.
If you don't study, you're gonna fail, right?
So, anyway, I think in the classroom my belief
is technology has to help us,
help the teacher, help the student.
And I do see the benefit,
positive has outweighed the concerns.
- [Leslie] Thank you.
And this is for Drew and Vinny.
How are you and your college partners using tech
and proactively outreaching to really connect
with students and help them succeed?
- Yeah.
- So, for context, Mainstay deploys AI coaches,
but I'm also quite an AI skeptic,
and particularly an AI skeptic about,
even digital twins, I will say.
So the origin story for Mainstay
is we were very interested in behavioral science
and the power of text messages
to help people overcome barriers through nudges.
But it turns out when you text young people,
hey, your FAFSA deadline is coming up, don't forget to file.
You end up getting lots and lots of questions back.
And our temptation and intuition was,
oh, we think we can use AI
to dramatically scale up the ability to handle this
and not need to hire additional staff members.
And I actually remember when our first customer
at Georgia State University, Tim Rennick, he asked me,
"Drew, is this going to work?"
And I said, "Tim, I have no idea.
(chuckles)
But let's find out."
And we brought on an outside researcher
to run a rigorous AB test called a randomized control trial
that we ended up publishing.
And sure enough, it did help.
And we've run a number of studies
and I could talk to you about our successes,
but actually the most important study we ever did
was the one that had the least impact.
And it was the only time
we did not consistently have a human being,
specifically the student's advisor or counselor
in the conversation as well.
We got overconfident and we thought,
oh, AI is capable of answering these things.
But it turns out the superpower of AI
is that people feel vulnerable and open with it.
I'm willing to say things to AI
that I wouldn't say to a person because I feel embarrassed.
And this is great,
but it turns out the flip side of this vulnerability
and non-judgment is actually non-accountability.
And without the human being in the conversation as well,
if I say, I promise I'll file my FAFSA by next Tuesday
and I don't follow through, I didn't let anybody down.
And so it's very interesting,
the temptation with AI is it can do a job,
but I think the next question used to be
is that a job that ought to be automated?
Just because it can be done doesn't mean it should be done.
And for instance, I guarantee you
Lee's digital twin could conduct today
a 100% flawless wedding ceremony.
And I'm sure nobody in this room
would want to be married by Lee's digital twin.
Sorry, Lee.
(attendees laughing)
Now, I'm gonna eat my words.
And tomorrow on Google News there's gonna be an article
about some digital twin marrying somebody.
But the fact is just because it can be done
doesn't mean it should be done.
And I think we need to be very cautious and skeptical
and rigorous in our measurement
of what the impacts actually are of certain things.
And maybe they are outstandingly impactful,
or maybe they inadvertently exacerbate problems
we don't know until we try.
And we have to know and measure carefully
to figure out the things that we should scale up,
or the things that we should absolutely stop doing.
Vinny? - Oh sure.
Yeah, thanks, Drew.
So at NetTutor, you know,
I wouldn't say I'm an AI skeptic
because we do use AI,
for example, in doing,
we can now review all of the sessions using AI,
and flag sessions that might be a problem
where five years ago that had to be done very manually,
which means we had to take sample sizes
and we couldn't really look
at a hundred thousand sessions a week.
And now we can review them all in flag ones
that we should go check.
We use AI in our queuing models
and some of other technology.
And of course, as a business we're using AI
for all types of things around sales and marketing,
business administration, data analysis.
When it comes to tutoring, however,
we are developing our lobby agent,
you know, if you know much about interaction with students,
in a tutoring model there's a certain number
of minutes required for me to figure out that you,
you know, that I know who you are,
that I can confirm what school you come from.
These are things that are tutors knows,
but we need to confirm, you know,
it looks like you came here for algebra.
Sometimes they say, no, I'm here for biology.
And you gotta go back and pick biology, you picked algebra.
And we're pretty confident that that can be done
with a large language model.
And then, so the first 5 to 10 minutes of the session
might be able to be done by some type of AI agent.
Schools, of course would be allowed to opt into this.
We wouldn't push this on schools as a way to save time.
And then, you could be turned over to a live tutor.
There's a piece in between
that we're certain, if I kind of know my answer,
I'm just stuck on the, I knew this formula yesterday,
I had forgotten it.
For sure ChatGPT, some of these other technologies,
that student who's ready to do the work
just needs to be reminded.
There's probably a really, really good opportunity
for them to get that question answered.
But if you know anything about tutoring,
and this is face-to-face tutoring,
this is advising when you're talking to a student,
and especially online tutoring,
when we say, how can I help you?
A lot of the sessions start with, I don't belong here.
And I do not believe
that we are even close to any type of AI model
that's gonna be able to turn on the video,
look at that student in the eyes and say,
listen, you do belong here and we're gonna do this together.
And I know that there's, you know,
empathy being built into AI that says good job.
And I heard, somebody was telling me that they were so proud
that AI is teaching students to say please and thank you.
That's all good and dandy and I support it all.
And I think that stuff is great.
And by the way, we also use AI for our support bot.
If you want to get tech support from us,
you know, we think we can get your question answered.
If not, then you can ask for an agent.
But the types of things
that happen in a real tutoring session,
the type of rapport you build,
I don't think we're close to being able to say.
And by the way, replace tutor with teacher
and all the teachers in the room will agree,
you know, AI can't teach.
AI can give you some instruction,
AI can ask you some questions,
but AI cannot do what a teacher does.
And so that's where we sort of,
and that tutor just kind of draw that line
and we're gonna go up to it
and maybe we'll go a little bit beyond it,
but at the end of the day,
we think that there's a human element
that it's not gonna go away for a while,
maybe someday.
(attendees applauding)
- Amen and hallelujah.
I would also add what is the job of a teacher?
Because it's not only,
and we talked about this earlier, Vinny,
not only being a subject matter expert,
I mean obviously people
are incredibly decorated to be faculty,
but the great teachers are the ones that motivate learners
to struggle a little bit more than they would on their own.
And that's second part is truly extraordinary
and really requires a human connection
and trust and empathy,
which AI might be able to mimic but can never replace.
And we just need to be very careful about the relationships
that we are developing and students are developing with AI.
It's worth noting that the number one use case,
it was number two last year
and it just became number one this year for Gen Z
is to use AI for companionship,
like the social replacement.
And they turn to it when they have good news
or they have a bad day.
And it is very interesting, possibly therapeutic,
but we've been down this road before with social media
where we thought we had a technology
that was going to bring us together
and it inadvertently driven us apart.
I think we should be very careful
and scrutinize what this technology is doing
to our social connections.
And so, you're right, like, anything that prevents us
from being human beings together
should be taken with a grain of salt.
- Thank you for that.
I'd like to expand on that just a little bit
and open it up to the panel.
Just the concept of ethics.
We always, I always get questions about, like, ethics,
and especially when it comes to like avatars
and digital twins.
So, you know, in your own personal expertise,
how, what are your thoughts on AI and ethics?
It's open to anyone. - Yeah.
- Well, I would just like to comment a little bit
about on ethical use of AI,
because when ChatGPT first came out,
the very very first thing we had to do
was reach out to all 500, 600 of our customers and say,
what is your AI policy?
And of course, 599 of them said, AI policy?
Should we have one of those?
Typing three prompts into ChatGPT,
taking what it spits out, copying and pasting the word,
and submitting it as your work is plagiarism, right?
Nobody argues that, I think we all know that.
I sat for the CPA exam in the eighties
and I wasn't allowed to use a calculator
because accountants should know how to do the math.
How dumb does that sound now, right?
Like, that was, this is not what we expect.
And so, ethical use of AI
is part of what we train our tutors to do using AI.
So for example, asking ChatGPT to help you,
you know, I have to write this,
can you give me some suggestions on prompts
or some sources that I might get
so where I can go do my work.
I mean, I think that's a good thing.
Some colleges may still prohibit that.
I mean, it's a college by college thing,
but so I think there's,
to me, yeah, there's always the right way
to do things.
Like, at the end of the day, if you think about,
there's a lot of ways to get there.
And I think students know,
and I think teachers know and I think tutors know-
- And that to an AI front end and have that dialogue.
What is your context, what is your direction,
why do you want to know the answer to that?
So, if a student asks me, I don't get it.
I mean, atoms are fundamentally empty.
So how are they hard and how could they weight so much?
And if I'm typically in lecture, thinking,
oh, God, this is a digression, right?
I turn that into a prompt and I teach the entire class.
There's actually an interesting piece here,
so let's have that conversation.
But when you go, as Michelle has said,
you don't ask an AI engine, why are atoms empty?
You might ask, what are they made of if they can be hard
and empty at the same time?
And turn that into a dialogue,
and then explore the composition of an atom.
- Yeah, just a quick follow up
that also when I think in the classroom,
a lot of teacher kind of facing, try to accuse student
of plagiarism or cheating because they have no control.
The way that I find that work out is,
I teach engineering graphics, right?
Solid work, it's a theory.
And those theory can be very, if I give like a 10-question,
like a final or a midterm, and say,
hey, describe what's orthographic view,
describe, you know, what is the thread, blah, blah, blah.
Those things can be done in five minutes just feeding to GPT
and then come back and everything's done.
But I didn't do that.
I said, we are gonna have oral exam,
and you can go look at GPT,
you can do modeling, you can write anything,
but the exam, you stand up there
and you explain to me verbally.
If you can remember all of the theory, you are done.
I don't care how you study it.
So we have to...
I kind of felt like I tell myself I have to change
the way that how I teach to accommodate technology
and what's available to student.
- That's great.
At Mainstay we have like our own internal,
we call it our hippocratic oath of AI.
I think we've had it for like five or six years.
And it's pretty simple actually.
And I'd encourage you to just think
about the principles for yourself,
what standards you wanna hold yourselves
and your colleagues to.
But it's things, like, start with why,
like, what are we trying to achieve
by implementing AI in a new area?
Because we're always trying to push the boundaries.
Although I'm the AI skeptic, we're still forging ahead.
We're just doing it with eyes wide open.
So start with why, what outcome are we hoping to achieve?
Do we wanna increase enrollment,
increase persistence to a degree, reduce DFW rates,
you name it, we wanna measure it.
The second is to be proactive.
If you create...
It's very much like the, build it and they will not come.
You have to actually bring the technology to people.
So typically the medium we use is text message.
We're pushing things to students directly
on their phones frequently.
And that is the way to reach the students
with the least help-seeking behavior.
Frankly, the students who are coming to your website
and interacting with a widget are the ones
who probably are going to solve the problem.
The ones you need to reach are the ones
who maybe aren't even thinking that they have a problem,
or don't know what they don't know.
College students often don't care until they care a lot
and then they don't really care again.
So how can you prompt them to care
and take advantage of those moments
when they're ready to engage?
The second is we're very cognizant
of wanting to enhance human relationships.
Like, are we getting in between people,
or we bringing people together?
And that's a question we ask ourselves all the time.
We are human-centered in the sense
that we want to center on relationships that humans have.
And then finally, we measure what matters
because the hippocratic oath suggests
that you should do no harm.
So what are the actual results you can think?
And even positive results
can be a distraction sometimes
because is it positive for everybody,
or is it only positive for some
and others are being left behind?
So being very cognizant of measuring the outcomes
for all students and all subgroups of students,
not just in aggregate.
And those tend to be the things that guide us,
but maybe something different guides you.
But I encourage you to think hard about,
hey, what really matters and what do you wanna hold true
whenever you're implementing AI
in a new way in your school, your classroom,
or any setting you have.
- Thank you for that.
You guys are getting great advice.
Here's one question, it's a little bit related to advice.
What's the best advice you'd give campus leaders
who want to adopt these tools, especially when there's fear
or resistance to new technology?
- I'll go for this.
Let me take a shot at this.
I may be offending all the leaders in the room.
What is the best advice from my technology perspective?
I think the attitude is very important.
Openness and the encouragement.
So let's say take a Chancellor Lee, I go up to him,
I say, I got this thing, right, this technology,
he could say, I'm not interested.
Guess what's gonna happen?
It brush under the rug.
Whether it's good or not, if he could say,
Michelle, go for it and let's see
what comes out of it, right?
So I go ahead and do something.
Maybe it's good, maybe it's bad,
but at least that's a really be open-minded, encouraged.
That's how the innovation happens.
One out of 10, maybe one out of a hundred ideas
is gonna be scale up like a Google for example 20 years ago.
You know, it's Google who cares about Google.
But somehow somebody gonna invest a lot of money
and that VC had made tons of money, right, super wealthy.
Was it Sequoia or A-to-Z or Mark Anderson?
So I think my advice is to just be open-minded,
be encouraging and supportive.
That's very important.
I mean you don't have to know everything,
but just know that we are here, we want to make impact,
and we want to make the world a better place to live.
Now we think about technology.
Chancellor Lambert said really well,
we want to make a impact, make a positive impact,
and let people use a technology tool, and to help people.
So that's what it is about.
- And building on that, I think that's great.
We've implemented AI at hundreds of institutions.
In many cases we're like the first AI implementation,
and there is always fear, uncertainty
and doubt at almost every level.
And I've learned there are like many, many ways to fail,
but there are only a few ways to succeed.
The surefire most reliable condition
for success is a culture of innovation.
And if you want to encourage a culture of innovation,
counterintuitively, I would strongly encourage any leader.
And frankly, we are all leaders, to celebrate failure.
And you're like, what, why failure?
Shouldn't we celebrate the success?
And you're right, like, one out of a hundred things
is going to succeed,
but there is no failure if you learn.
And if you shine a spotlight
and celebrate the people who are taking the risks,
and have them, from the mountaintops,
shout what they have learned.
Because no matter what, if you learn you have not failed,
you have advanced the ball forward.
And at least help someone else not step
in the same pothole that you did.
The culture of innovation that we've seen work the best
are places that are constantly experimenting
and celebrating not just the successes
but actually giving more attention to the things
that didn't get off the ground
or didn't fully accomplish what they set out to do.
It's counterintuitive, but it is a sure-fire way
to succeed in an uncharted territory.
- Yeah, thank you.
So when I have this conversation,
you know, I think there's two parts to the conversation.
The first is that our pace
at which we adopt technology is so fast now
that I don't think we want to do this
isn't really a great answer
as an academic leader or any kind of leader
'cause maybe you don't, but the students are gonna do it.
And if you bury your head, you're only hurting yourself.
I mean I just, we launched online tutoring in 1996,
and I would call schools
and I would say it works on the 9,600 bod modem.
So, if you know what that is, then you're as old as I am.
And they said, "That's great.
Nobody has internet in our school."
Well, we don't hear that today.
So to avoid AI
is just a terrible mistake at any level
of an institution because it's happening.
The students are doing to, like, get into it.
In terms of a real warning though,
you know, who's ever going to do this,
whatever they're going to do,
they're presumably gonna be a lot of smart people
and they're gonna plan for the successes,
and they're gonna tell you
all the things you're gonna get out of it,
and they're gonna tell you the risks,
and they're gonna tell you how they're gonna avoid
all the risks.
It's the unintended consequences.
- Yeah. - You know, you don't know
what you don't know until it happens.
And you know, that happened with ChatGPT
when it first came out,
and then all of a sudden the next thing you know ChatGPT
is saying some pretty terrible things
they didn't think it would say.
They didn't realize that that was just AI being AI.
And so, they put some filters on it.
And so, whether it's your avatars
or whether it's anything I do,
or, you know, just you don't know what might happen,
good or bad.
You might find really good unintended consequences.
But those need to be planned for, prepared for,
and then you just have to kind of fess up that it happened
and then figure out how you're gonna fix it or regroup
or take it down before you put it back up.
That's usually the way the conversations I have go.
- Okay, so what challenges come up
when you try to scale these innovations
across multiple departments or campuses?
- People. - Yeah.
People are the problem, but they can also be the solution.
So at Georgia State University,
they were our first partner.
They actually have a really wonderful policy.
So they set up, and we're coaching
at their campus about 50,000 students.
And they are incredibly clear.
Like this is a line of text messaging
directly to every student in an instant.
And as soon as a word got out that this was successful,
the football coach said, "Well, we got a game on Saturday,
we gotta get the word out, get people to the stadium."
And another department came and said,
"Well, we wanna message them."
And the risk is that we would do to this medium
the same thing we did to email,
which is encourage students to tune out
because it is full of things that they don't care about.
So the value of texting, for example,
is that its strength is also, its like really narrow limits
and you have to focus the messaging.
So what they did is they actually had one person
for the entire campus in charge
of what messages went through our platform,
and they gave her the mandate,
if it isn't designed to achieve student success,
meaning help more students persist to a degree,
the answer is no.
And having a clear why they are doing what they are doing
was the thing that allowed them to say no to everything else
so that they could say hell yes
to the very small subset of things
that were actually going to achieve the goal.
And the number one advice I always give to people
is start with why and never deviate from it.
Know what your north star is.
And I would say that is the best way to cut through,
like the murky territory of, like, human beings
all having their own competing priorities particularly,
and when something is gaining traction,
like everyone wants to pile on, less is often more.
- Yes, absolutely, I agree.
From the higher leadership level, I think we,
it's very important to provide a clear common vision
that the people under the leadership
had this common view and common goal,
knowing that where we are going.
Even though cross-functional cross department
may not agree with the priority,
but we know that from the leader, the captain of the ship,
to say this is the direction we're gonna go.
I think that will help a lot in the collaboration
of each department, each schools even.
So I think from that level it is very important.
At the lower level,
I think of what's important things,
for example, we do this pilot project, right?
When you start in trial and run,
when you have a success, you celebrate it,
you advertise it, you tell people to say,
hey, we did this and this is a successful,
and you will benefit this.
This is a way to convince the people
that your cross department, your colleague that to jump in.
And of course they have maybe some incentive
that's up to the management.
But I think also once the people see the benefit,
they will be able to more willing
to cooperate to convince the people.
But if you can't, you can't force anyone
to do something that they don't believe in.
So you gotta have to say, this is what I did,
and this is how I benefited, marketing, advertisement.
- Yeah. - Thank you.
- Neither carrot, nor stick, but FOMO.
(all laughing)
- Yeah. - Yeah.
So what I think with any special technology,
but it's true for anything too.
The biggest challenge in scaling
is that when you pilot something
or if you're the designer of it or you're early in,
you think it's a great idea.
And you love the idea and you fall in love with your idea,
and then you believe that everybody's gonna believe
that this is a good idea.
And if they don't, my PowerPoint deck is gonna show them
what a good idea this is.
And the fact is it doesn't have to be a bad idea
for other people to not care, not like it,
not wanna do it. - Yeah.
- And so to scale, I'll give you a perfect example,
I have four children all in their twenties and a wife
and we have five iPhone users and one Samsung user.
And my kids say, "Dad, I can't find your phone
and we can't FaceTime."
And I'm like, "I know."
(attendees laughing)
See what they thought was a great idea
that they were gonna convince me,
turned out to be the exact opposite of what I thought.
I don't want you to find my phone,
it's none your business where I am.
You're a grownup, I'm a grownup, leave me alone.
So anyways, that's why I think that,
I think that tends to be the biggest challenge.
And I imagine you guys
will experience this too with digital twins,
is that it might fit in some departments.
Other departments, it won't be a good fit for.
Some classes, maybe it's okay to send your students
to something virtual to get answers.
Other kind of classes,
I think students might find themselves entirely offended
that their teacher won't directly respond to their email,
and then being sent to an avatar.
So I think, doesn't mean it's not a great idea
and it doesn't mean it doesn't work
in certain circumstances, but I think,
you know, global adaptation of anything,
it just gets hard the bigger you try to spread it.
- Absolutely, I agree with that.
Adoption is always follow Gaussian model,
you know the bell curve.
You have the beachhead,
the top 5% that just graphed, adopting everything emergent.
Then you have the 90%
of the bell curve in the middle, right?
Then you always have that 5% no matter what you're gonna do,
they're not gonna be on the ship.
So I think we should allow everybody
making their own decision and they decide
when they want to join and when they want to move.
- I also think the question we ask is important
because oftentimes we're saying,
and the news is terrible and the headline is AI achieves,
blah, blah, blah outcome.
Or I remember when we had our first summer melt thing,
it's like AI solve summer melt for Georgia State.
Well, AI didn't do anything, Human beings did it.
And the question isn't does AI work or not?
It's what are the exact conditions
under which AI can achieve this particular outcome?
And it turns out AI can be really helpful,
but there are 14 things you've gotta do
and there's a order you have to do them
and there's a recipe for success.
And oftentimes that just doesn't fit the headline.
And so, I think the question we ask is,
hey, what are the exact conditions?
Which course, what size, what subject, et cetera.
Where this is gonna work really well?
And that allows somebody who has something similar to say,
oh, it might work in my setting too.
- Yeah, we did the sub pilot project.
I can share exactly where it adapts well,
and where it didn't adapt a well.
But I may not wanna share it right now,
but, yeah, I know exactly where it is gonna adapt well
and where is not gonna adapt well.
Okay, English. - You're keeping it a secret.
- English is not gonna adapt well because English,
LLM is a large language model.
It has all the English literature,
you know, from 800 years and compile into two days.
And it has a mass amount of vocabulary wording,
and even have a good college level of thinking.
- Yes. - Verbal thinking.
So the English definitely would not adapt well
to say that we're not gonna use AI.
But with AI you do replace a lot of classical,
or legacy English teaching curriculum.
That's my thinking.
And then now, as you talk about engineering or chemistry.
Engineering, for example, I'm familiar with engineering,
we are still far behind on the engineering logic AI,
the critical thinking AI,
and that part hasn't been, the AI hasn't catch up yet.
So we can use that to leverage some of the aid
for our teaching.
And computer science adapt really quite well.
I mean, when we did this pilot project we have,
the fastest adopter are computer science professor.
They're very talented, they figure out everything,
they just, boom, it come, it just comes out.
So they adopted quickest. - Thank you.
I'd like to open this up to our audience.
Do you have any questions for our panelists today?
Yes.
(attendee speaking indistinctly)
And we just opened our first OpenAI lab last week.
- Cool. - And so we're excited
about using AI.
And so with that being said, every flex event,
the department head of AI and I we're like doing our best
to kind of like encourage our staff,
the students and our,
you know, colleagues in the institution
and in the industry to kind of like be open with AI.
Now my question is, are we kind like redefining our role
and responsibility as educators?
Because it boils down to when we present,
not everyone are acceptable with the idea.
And most of the time, like, there are refusals,
and we'll hear kind of like you're adding work
to what we're doing right now.
So with that being said, with a teacher saying that,
and me, like, formulating this kind of like,
I'm doing like a no-code app right now,
utilizing MP six five, which is really cool.
And I'm trying to kind of like teach that tool,
but then there's some refusal
with those technology or tools.
And with that formative assessment
being offered to my students,
the students won't do such formative assessments
without me giving kind of like an incentive
or a grade to that.
So I just wanted to go back
into our definition of as an educator
'cause everything was down to the same course policy,
and now we're adding AI policy.
But how many in this room have developed their AI policy?
So I just wanted to go back to that as a baseline.
- [Leslie] Actually, I'd like to ask the room,
how many of you
have a course policy on AI?
- Wow. - What about
a department policy when you're working together as teams?
What about an institutional AI policy?
Okay, how many of you have a personal AI policy?
I love that, okay, thank you.
But yes, that's definitely something
that has to be revisited.
And I don't think it's something
that we should only do as individuals
because again, we're using AI together, right?
This is the world where AI is just now a part of our teams.
It's a part of our ecosystem.
And the more that we are all on the same page,
the easier it's gonna be for our students
to work with us, right?
- Can I plug the last panel?
I don't know how many of you all were in here
for the last panel, but it was freaking awesome.
I mean, and the person who was the faculty member in,
I think English composition was like a master class
in how to run a course with AI.
Yeah, you're nodding back there.
And he even cited this list.
I was trying to write it down.
So if anyone knows it,
of like the 150 different policies from courses.
What was it? - Dr. Lance Eaton.
- Dr. Lance Eaton?
- E-A-T-O-N. - E-A-T-O-N.
- [Attendee 1] You'll find him on Substack.
- On Substack, Dr. Lance Eaton.
I was like, I wanna find that.
Check that out, you'll get 150 different policies
that you can learn from and hopefully assemble your own.
Great to get inspiration, thank you.
- [Leslie] Yes.
- [Attendee 2] So I have a comment and a question
and I also just wanna,
I was in the digital twin pilot
that Michelle was talking about.
I was the one English person on there.
So I just wanna say there are applications in English,
but you just have to, it's a different problem
that we're trying to solve if you're using digital twins
or anything like that, AI.
So my question for the panel is,
what is the problem that you think
a digital twin could solve?
- That's on my next slide. - Oh.
- Oh, go for it. - If you don't mind.
- Yeah, there you go.
While you're looking for that, I'll see your problem.
So I made a digital twin once.
We have James at my company,
he's a senior product manager and he is a rock star.
And every time somebody has a product question in Slack,
James is answering, like, in five minutes,
he's unbelievable.
And I thought, oh, man, James is so incredible.
He's got all this knowledge in his head.
I should just, like, scrape everything he's ever said
in Slack and create like a digital James
to save him a ton of time
'cause that's actually not his job
to answer those questions.
His job's to build the product of the future.
And I built it and I showed it to him and he hated it.
(attendees laughing)
He was like, I can't believe...
He's like, "One, this is cool.
Do not show this to anyone, do not let anyone use it."
And I was like, "James, why?
This is gonna save you so much time."
And he said, "No, I like the questions."
And I was like, "But they're distracting you."
He goes, "Drew, you don't understand.
These are opportunities for me to connect with my coworkers
and often uncover things that I never would've understood
about our product until I ask the second
and third order questions and went deeper with them.
So you only see the questions and answers in the main thing,
but, like, these are opportunities that I'm servicing
to learn things that I couldn't learn any other way."
And I was like, "Oh, yeah, you're right."
So I scrapped it.
But it's interesting
that you can have unintended consequences.
But yeah, I'd love to know.
(Michelle speaking indistinctly)
Thank you so much for asking.
I had the thought about this beforehand.
What problem are we solving?
We talk about digital twin, we talk about anything,
any entrepreneur you would know
when they come up to their 32nd pitch
or their five minutes presentation,
the first thing they say, what problem are we having?
What is the solution?
What problem are we solving using the digital twin?
So from only the education college level,
we have reduced the faculty and staff workload.
When I first started
with the Foothill College last September,
I have this teacher, was very kindly mentor me to say,
you need to do this, this, this, this.
By the way, I have 50 student, I'm so stressed out,
I'm overworked and I try to set up 20 minutes
with each student per quarter.
That's a thousand minutes.
So then immediately I say, okay, I have,
my mind to say, how can I solve this problem, right?
So when you have a digital twin, I say,
you could have maybe something automated
and talk to the student, gather the feedback,
and keep the log and then you can review it
instead of face-to-face.
The second is increase the student support level.
Digital twin can have 24 by 7 support.
It doesn't get sick, It doesn't require office hour.
And also it's very scalable.
When you physical person, you meet student one-on-one,
digital twin can span off 50 sessions,
meet with 50 student at the same time, it's scalable.
So definitely increase the student level support.
Also, college, you have a financial benefit.
You cost a saving on the college tutoring budget.
We think about money, right?
Then, you can bridging the technology gap.
That's a little kind of like an insulting part for me,
or for somebody.
Student, I found out they adapted technology faster than us
on some certain situation.
For example, when Gemini,
Google IO announced their Gemini workflow,
the flow, canvas flow, I was like so excited.
I said, oh, you know, you can do this, this, this, this.
The student in the classroom pull up the laptop,
they sign it up, they say,
"Oh, I just created this amazing video with one prompt.
Have the Superman fighting a giant spider."
The movie comes out.
So they're very quick.
And for me, I have to kind of like go on
and take a look at it and think about it.
So with the digital twin, it's kind of play in between.
It does bridge the gap between a faculty and student.
That's just my personal opinion.
- I wonder if I could-
- Yes. - Yes, sure.
- Awesome, thank you for that question.
I would like to introduce an idea.
A little bit orthogonal,
but straight Tess's question.
Imagine, well, we don't have to imagine.
There is a digital twin for every car
that's ever been manufactured, currently running right now,
there's a digital twin for every commercial airplane.
Southwest Airlines has a digital twin for every 737.
And I believe that in addition
to simulating mechanical systems for predictive analytics
and intervening just in time
before maintenance becomes critical,
that there are industries
where representing people, animate objects, say healthcare,
Kaiser is probably thinking about digital twins of patients.
We think that we're unique and we're not.
There are 50 or 100 people just like us,
maybe a little older, a little younger.
They may look a little bit different,
but metabolically they're the same.
We have the same challenges and we have arcs
and we can predict what's going on.
And that's what digital tunes
have been used since, in NASA, right?
For 20 years for understanding something's way out there.
And we're gonna figure out down here what's going on.
Now, imagine digital twins of students.
Imagine guided pathways, follow the yellow brick road.
Just take chem 38, then take biology.
And in a year and a half you'll be ready in nursing school
or something like that.
That's the guided pathway, but it's not the true path.
Our students are more like pinballs
and they may ricochet off courses
and they have issues that come up.
They all have talents.
But if we could represent students in a virtual world,
this is not a new idea.
In 1991, Michael Gelernter came up with this idea,
in a book called "Mirror World",
and showed it with Christina.
And this idea was actually stimulated by Lee Lambert
who mentioned this word about maybe a year ago.
And I thought, heck, that is so interesting.
What if we represented molecules?
And I thought, wait a minute, I'm in education.
What if we represented students
and really took all, not their transcripts,
but in addition to that, their abilities,
their associations, their affinity groups.
Do they have internships?
Where do they work?
Do they have housing insecurity?
And imagine a world where we can represent students
not knowing their names,
but representing them and predicting their trajectories
and showing really firsthand
what interventions are successful.
So I just wanna wrap up with,
this is a project that I've been working on
for about a month now, spurned by Lee's idea a while back.
Hit me up afterwards Because I believe
that we can represent students.
I think that there are industries, were already doing it,
healthcare, criminal justice, recovery.
Why are we not doing it in education?
We know our lives are messy, right?
We know our students have challenging lives.
Can we see that in an action?
And can we feed those digital twins
and no one to provide support services?
- [Leslie] Thank you.
(Vinny speaking indistinctly)
- Quickly, yes. - Oh, nevermind.
- [Leslie] Oh, well, is it okay with the...
I just wanna say we're two minutes over.
Okay, so thank you everyone.
I know that today we talked about digital twins.
We started off with the concept of J.A.R.V.I.S.
And I want you to understand, at some point,
we all may have a digital twin,
but before we create them, I just wanna encourage you
to understand what your superpower is first, right?
Understand, like, as Iron Man, as Iron Woman,
what are you bringing to serve our students, who are you?
And then, create your digital twin.
And if you don't know, you could easily just ask ChatGPT.
I did, right?
So it's a simple prompt,
and you could let it say something like,
Iron Man has J.A.R.V.I.S.,
I want a digital twin.
Knowing what you know about me, describe my digital twin.
And it gave me a whole list of information.
But what I wanna end with is this,
how it introduces itself on stage.
If I had a digital twin right now, it would say,
hi Leslie, I'm your bridge keeper.
I map the work like a twin, nudge like a mentor,
and protect like a steward.
I will suggest, you will decide.
Today's risks are noted, your voice is loaded,
and your people stay at the center.
So thank you for joining us today.
If you have any questions,
please come up and see our panelists.
(attendees applauding)